The first casualty of war is the truth.
Under Fire is a drama, war film directed by Roger Spottiswoode.
journalists get too close to one another and their work in 1979 Nicaragua.
Russell Price, played by Nick Nolte.
Alex Grazier, played by Gene Hackman.
Claire, played by Joanna Cassidy.
Oates, played by Ed Harris.
Marcel Jazy, played by Jean-Louis Trintignant.
Hub Kittle, played by Richard Masur.
Under Fire is a 1983 American political thriller film set during the last days of
the Nicaraguan Revolution that ended the Somoza regime in 1979.
Directed by Roger Spottiswoode, it stars Nick
Nolte, Gene Hackman and Joanna Cassidy.
The musical score by Jerry Goldsmith, which featured jazz guitarist Pat
Metheny, was nominated for an Oscar for Best Original Score.
The editing by Mark Conte and John Bloom was nominated
for a BAFTA Award for Best Editing.
The film was shot in the Mexican states of Chiapas and Oaxaca.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship, war
correspondent, 1970s, revolution, war photographer.
The tone is emotional.